DANISH SHAIKH (M.B.A, SOCPA, B.COM)

CASTLE MILL ROAD, THANE (W), STATE: MAHARASHTRA, COUNTRY: INDIA 400601 | (H) 912225374404 | (C) +91 9136213416 | ms.dnshaikh@qmail.com



PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Proficient Corporate Finance Manager who has more than 9 years of experience with exceptional background in utilizing data from diverse financial and information systems to build tools and forecasting models that remarkably improve organizational decision-making capabilities resulting in increased profitability. Demonstrated track record providing comprehensive financial forecasting, budgeting, and analysis to senior management at Fortune 500 organizations.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Budget & Statistical analysis expert
- Knowledge of ERP (Enterprise Resource Planning) software
- Financial Planning and Strategy
- Expertise in Accounting Software usage SAP FICO, BW, Oracle, Cognos.
- Process Improvement, Cost Accounting

- Highly developed Microsoft Suite skills (Word, Excel, PPT)
- Proficient in preparation of Final accounts, Budgeting, MIS, Variance Analysis
- Skilled in computing, analyzing and interpreting complex data, and Financial modelling.
- Extensive Experience in Handling Banking Relationship (Trade Finance), Internal Audit.

WORK HISTORY

SEPTEMBER -2013- CURRENT

Financial Analyst at Landmark Arabia, Riyadh, Gulf



- Develops the forecasting tools and dashboards to analyze revenue variance, business pipeline and industry trends.
- Designs the Annual Financial Budget for the turnover of over SAR 5 billion.
- Determines cost of operations by establishing standard costs; collecting operational data.
- Release the financial reports- P&L, Balance sheet on monthly & quarterly basis.
- Analyzes the financial ratios, trend & variance comparison, review of accounts, ledger scrutiny, and preparation of cash flow management reports.
- Cash flow planning & working capital, Stock cover analysis
- Budgets active and proposed projects by accurately determining pricing, margins and risk factors.
- Devises the feasibility reports (BEP) for new projects
- Reorganized the Inventory management relevant reports
- Fixed Asset Database management.
- Led monthly meetings with directors to analyze spending and provide financial recommendations.
- Curtailed the Forecasts report to a more accurate, efficient and automated layout, Periodic updates for overheads budget and assessment of likely year end spend.
- Facilitates the Ad Hoc projects as requested by Business Controller and the Finance Director Coordinates the period, quarterly and year end close processes, Period close analysis
- Managed, tracked and monitored financial updates, watch lists and insurance files.
- Built and maintained databases for forecasting the financial performance

FEBRUARY 2011- SEPTEMBER 2013

Deputy Finance Manager

Reliance Industries Limited, Ghansoli, Navi Mumbai



- Facilitated the timely provisioning, closing of books & Submission of Quarterly & Monthly Financial statements i.e. Trial Balance, Profit & Loss A/c, Balance Sheet, Schedules
- Designed the creditors & debtors ageing report to the management for the turnover over INR 3000 crores.
- Reconciled the records with vendors and clients on a timely basis for transactions over INR 100 crores.
- Developed the financial budget procedures & presented "what if" scenarios for budget assumptions and forecasting strategies.
- Cultivated the Variance analysis report with the budgets to the senior management.
- Facilitated the month-end close processes, Invoicing, journal entries and account reconciliation.
- Improved the spreadsheet models for diverse projects and analysis.
- Built and maintained databases for forecasting future financial performance.
- Generated the quarterly earning presentations and monthly investor presentations.
- Consolidated the financial data and materials for key leadership meetings.

AUGUST 2008- FEBRUARY 2011

Finance Executive

Enercon India Limited (Gmbh) Andheri, Mumbai



- Controlled the Trade Finance Banking limits, Letter of credit, RTGS/NEFT arrangement with bank
- Designed and created daily, weekly and monthly cash flow reports.
- Facilitated the fund & non-fund based limit utilization reports, Quarterly inventory reports to the management.
- Developed the accounts payable reports for management review supported the accounting department during monthly closings.
- Handled Opex Budget of over INR 100 crores.
- Developed the daily/weekly spending forecasting mechanism Liaison with top 10 bankers for trade finance activities.
- Cultivated the Adhoc reports to the management based on different requirements,
- Structured the bank reconciliation process for monthly review.
- Created and maintained precise and accurate models, charts and reports.
- Led monthly meetings with directors to analyze spending and provide financial recommendations.

EDUCATION

2008

MBA: Finance

Institute of Management & Computer Studies, Mumbai

Internship: Project Name- Hydel Power Projects "Corporate Finance" At Hindustan Construction Company

2006

Bachelor of Commerce: Major Subject "Financial Accounting & Auditing"

University of Mumbai

Scored distinction in university

Other Certification

Certificate of Achievement -Financial Planning by "TAFEI SYDNEY"- Open Universities Australia. Honor Code Certificate- Financial Analysis and Decision Making by "Tsinghua University".

Registered as a Member at **SOCPA Institute**

I hereby certify that the above information is true & best of my knowledge & belief.